thenortheasttoday.com 2019-04-11

# Privacy Policy - TNT-The NorthEast Today

Our Policy

This Privacy Policy relates to the services that www.thenortheasttoday.com (TNT) provides to buyers and sellers on the thenortheasttoday Audience Management Platform. Through the Data Marketplace, advertisers, publishers, and content providers leverage anonymous audience data to reach specific audiences for content delivery and interest based advertising.

To view our Website Privacy Policy, please click here.

Our Services

thenortheasttoday provides data collection, data segmentation, and data distribution to facilitate interest based advertising for advertisers, publishers, and content providers (our customers) and provide a more relevant advertising experience to consumers. In order to provide these services, thenortheasttoday collects information about users’ online activity across websites and mobile applications

Information Collection

We collect thenortheasttoday Audience Targeting Data from our partners (such as publishers, mobile app developers, and other third-party providers of advertising technology and services) in a variety of ways, including through the use of browser cookies, pixels, application software development kits (SDKs), or server-to-server connections with our partners.

Cookies. Cookies are small text files that are stored on a user’s Internet browser, and can be accessed by web servers when the browser returns to a website or goes to another website. Cookies are used by companies to gather information about visits to websites – for example, number of visits, average time spent, pages viewed, navigation history through the website, and other statistics. This information helps companies to improve a user’s online experience in many ways: for example, by making the website easier to use, measuring the effectiveness of promotional ad placements, and tailoring websites and advertisements to better match a user’s interests and preferences.

Pixel Tags. Pixel tags are small strings of html or JavaScript code that provide a method for delivering a graphic image on a Web page or other document. Pixel tags allow the operator of the Web page or other document, or a third party who serves the pixel tag, to set, read, and modify the thenortheasttoday Targeting Cookies. Pixel tags may also be used to gather information about the computer being used to view that Web page such as the time a tag was sent, the user’s operating system and browser type, and similar information. SDK. A SDK is a piece of code that exists within an application on a mobile device to provide functionality for the application. One function can be to collect data and transmit information to third parties such as thenortheasttoday. This information may include mobile advertising identifiers (e.g., Apple’s IDFA and Google Advertising ID), IP addresses, time stamp, general (not precise) location information derived from IP address, as well as information regarding your use of publisher apps, which may provide us with information to draw inferences about your commercial interests. thenortheasttoday also receives data collected by or from your mobile devices.

Server to Server connections. thenortheasttoday also may obtain data from other online and offline third-party sources directly through connections to their servers through various secure information transfer methods. thenortheasttoday does not collect personally identifiable information from users through its service. thenortheasttoday also does not store personally identifiable information such as name, address, telephone number, social security number, or e-mail address.

We collect your public profile data only from your consent that you grant before initiating Social Login, from the social network used to login at our website. This data includes your first name, last name, email address, link to your social media profile, unique identifier, link to social profile avatar. You can revoke this consent at any time by sending us an email. We embed Facebook Comments plugin to allow you to leave comment at our website using your Facebook account. This plugin may collect your IP address, your web browser User Agent, store and retrieve cookies on your browser, embed additional tracking, and monitor your interaction with the commenting interface, including correlating your Facebook account with whatever action you take within the interface (such as “liking” someone’s comment, replying to other comments), if you are logged into Facebook. For more information about how this data may be used, please see Facebook’s data privacy policy: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update

thenortheasttoday uses and may combine the information collected by various means, including from third party data sources, to help customers create a more relevant advertising and online experience for the user.

How We Use Collected Information

We and our customers use thenortheasttoday Targeting Data to provide more relevant advertising or content to users. For example, we may use information about your visits to multiple unaffiliated websites to infer the types of ads and content that may interest you. We also may use the information collected in browsers for advertising, analytics, or ad reporting purposes, or to improve the services.

We may use information about your activity across multiple unaffiliated third-party mobile applications to predict the types of advertisements that may interest you. We share this information, and information about your visits to multiple, unaffiliated sites, with advertisers, publishers, and content providers (our customers) to specify an ad, a group of ads, or content to be displayed to a particular computer or device. thenortheasttoday and its partners also may use such information for advertising, analytics, or ad reporting purposes, or to improve the services. We may combine this information with a mobile advertising identifier (such as your mobile device’s IDFA or Google Advertising ID) and may retain it for up to 90 days since the date of last activity.

thenortheasttoday uses standard non-sensitive health segments to deliver interest-based advertisements to users in web browsers and mobile applications.

Cross-Device Matching

thenortheasttoday may use data it collects or receives from advertising technology partners and customers, including publishers, to make a deterministic or statistical match of mobile advertising identifiers and cookie identifiers. For example, thenortheasttoday or its partners may match your devices if you log into the same online service on multiple devices or web browsers, or if your devices share similar attributes that support an inference that they are used by the same user.

We also may use such information to match a user’s interests across devices, as well as for analytics, ad reporting, or to improve the services.

Choices and Opting Out

Web Browsers

You may opt out of thenortheasttoday’s data collection and use of Targeting Cookies for interest-based advertising purposes. You may also manage your advertising preferences in web browsers by adjusting the interest-based segments that we associate with your browser or device.

Please note that by opting out from thenortheasttoday, you are opting out of ad and content targeting activities that are conducted online via thenortheasttoday services. You will still receive online advertisements and content, but these ads and content may not be as relevant to you. Be advised that if you change computers or browsers, or use multiple computers or browsers or delete your cookies, you will need to repeat this process for each computer and each browser. You may download a browser plugin that will help you maintain your opt out choices, even if you delete certain cookies from your browser, by visiting http://www.aboutads.info/PMC.

thenortheasttoday effectuates do not track signals set in certain browsers by stopping collection of web viewing data for providing relevant advertising. thenortheasttoday currently applies signals set in Chrome, Firefox, Safari, and certain versions of Internet Explorer. thenortheasttoday does not apply signals set in Internet Explorer version 10 and above.

Mobile Applications

If you would like to opt-out of thenortheasttoday’s interest-based advertising in mobile applications, you can download the Digital Advertising Alliance’s mobile application for each of your devices and set your preferences in the application.

Download AppChoices for iOS devices

Download AppChoices for Android devices

If you reset the mobile advertising identifiers (e.g., Apple’s IDFA and Google Advertising ID), you will also need to reset your preferences in the AppChoices applications.

Cross-Device Matching Opt-out

If you would like to opt out of thenortheasttoday’s cross-device matching, you may do so by opting out using the tools identified in each of the “Web Browsers” and “Mobile Applications” sections above.

When you opt out using the tools for web browsers and mobile applications, thenortheasttoday will disassociate the information collected on the browser or device from which you have opted out from the other browsers or devices that thenortheasttoday may have matched to it (similarly, thenortheasttoday will disassociate the information collected on other browsers or devices from the device from which you have opted out). To opt-out on all of your browsers and devices that thenortheasttoday may have matched, please opt out separately on each device and each browser that you use.

Sharing Information with Third Parties

thenortheasttoday may share information that we collect through or in connection with the services with third parties for a variety of purposes, as described below.

thenortheasttoday may share thenortheasttoday Targeting Data, and information derived from Targeting Data, with our customers in the ordinary course of our business. We indicate to our customers that an thenortheasttoday targeting cookie or mobile advertising identifier is a member of an thenortheasttoday Targeting Data segment at various times. For example, a particular browser or device may be associated as a member of a segment (e.g., interests in Green Living or Movies) when the browser or device visits certain Web pages or mobile applications that are operated by our customers. Our customers may use a browser’s or device’s associated membership within a segment of inferred commercial interests based on browsing activity across unaffiliated websites or mobile apps over time to display advertisements and other content that are related to that segment. Customers may also use other partners acting on behalf of those customers to display advertising or other content that reflects a browser’s or device’s membership in a segment.  
thenortheasttoday may share Targeting Data with third-party service providers (e.g., data storage and processing facilities) to perform business functions for us or on our behalf.  
thenortheasttoday may also disclose Targeting Data if we believe that we have a legal obligation to do so or where necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process.  
In the event thenortheasttoday merges with another company, or another company acquires all or substantially all of thenortheasttoday’s assets, including, without limitation, in the event of bankruptcy, all data compiled or owned by thenortheasttoday may be among the items transferred in that transaction.  
Data Storage, Retention, and Security

Except as otherwise stated in this policy, thenortheasttoday may store the data it collects on its servers. thenortheasttoday may retain anonymous log file data, including cookie data, web browsing data, and mobile browsing data (including data from app usage) for up to 120 days for ad targeting purposes. Aggregated data may be retained for other purposes, including analytics, for up to 13 months.

thenortheasttoday uses generally accepted industry security standards including physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to help protect our data. No security measures, however thorough, are perfect, and there can be no absolute assurance of security.

Children

The services provided by thenortheasttoday are not intended for persons under 13 years of age. thenortheasttoday’s products and services are not developed or directed at children. We do not knowingly solicit or collect personally identifiable information including not from children under the age of 13, nor do we market our products or services to children under the age of 13.

Changes to Our Policy

We may revise this Policy at any time. We encourage you to visit this page periodically to review our current Policy so that you may know what information we gather and how we may use that information.

Contacting Us

Should you have questions in regards to this Policy or thenortheasttoday’s privacy practices, please contact us at: thenortheasttodayeditor@gmail.com

Updated: June 11, 2016, Effective March 18, 2016
